

I've worked as and Electrical Engineer for twenty years at multinational companies, at small family business and also have experience working as a freelancer. During my professional career I've always enjoyed the programming and IT related tasks the most. I'm an innovative and technology driven professional seeking an entry-level remote software engineer position. I've learned that the end of the day the only thing that matters is results. I've decided to take a Fullstack Web Development course and build some real applications. At the end of the course I will develop 8 webapps. For the deatails and updates please see my website.



#### **Teamwork and Communication**

In most of my career I was working in team. Big, small, multinational and multicultural. I've learned how to communicate with them efficiently. My friendly and positive attitude has boosted the levels of teamwork and has helped increase organizational productivity. Represented the company in front of international customers at site surveys, during factory acceptance tests and commissionings.

## Adaptability

I had several positions in different workplaces and worked on abroad for shorter periods that make me to adapt to various environments and requirements.

#### Decision-making

Specially as a Project Engineer I had to make many decisions during project exectuion and consider both the customer's and my employers best intrest.

#### Technology literacy

I I've dealt with a lot of different technologies and I've learned everything outside school. I'm feeling confortable with working and learning with technical documentation or even cerating one. As a project engineer I've always had to think in systems and not only in individual technical devices and see how all of the parts are working together.



EXPERIENCES

Vác. Hungary

Freelancer February 2022 - Present

Taking the Full-Stack Web Development Program at CareerFoundry. I also accepting small electrical engineer contracts to get some financial support during the career

#### Gas Turbine Controls Project Engineer

Baker & Hughs - Fót, Hungary

• Project leading of Gas turbine control system upgrades and participation in couple of DCS contors upgrade. International projects in Energy and Oil & Gas industry around the world (with customers like Chevron, Linde, Sonatrach, Sonelgaz, EDF, Exxon, etc...)

- Mark IV and Mark V migrations and complete control system upgrades to Mark VIe (GE latest Control System). Integrate external systems like Excitation, Generator Control, Fire Protection Panel ...
- HMI and network topology design including PLC / Control System configuration / programming
- Visual Basic programming for large data handling in Microsoft Excel
- Site survey/study and data collection, design review meetings with customers, managing technical team during project execution
- Continuous communication with customer's stakeholders and with our international engineering team
- Prepare and lead the customer witnessed Factory Acceptance Test and site commissioning support
- Developed internal processes and plans for mechanical verification, product development and factory processes

## Control Cabinet Hardware Designer

GE Oil & Gas - Fót, Hungary

December 2009 - June 2012

June 2012 - March 2018

- Local Control Panel / Cabinet design of Mark VIe Gas Turbine Control Systems and Bently Nevada Vibration Monitoring System packages
- Electrical / control / automation system design, following the related international and local standards. Design documents, diagrams, loop drawings, schematics in AutoCAD,AutoCAD Electrical, Autodesk Inventor and EPLAN. Managing the Bill of material and Material Masters in ERP (SAP)
- Supporting of the manufacturing process and the test of the control cabinets. Monitored company inventory to keep stock levels and databases updated.
- Resolved problems, improved operations and provided exceptional service.

## Manufacturing Support Engineer

GE Energy - Veresegyház, Hungary

June 2007 - November 2009

- Aero Derivative Gas turbine package's BOM managment in the corporate's ERP system (Oracle)
- Communicating with production planning and requisition engineering teams. Collaborated with team members to achieve target results. Participate in technical training in Houston HQ.
- Material sourcing technical support, create technical documentation to outsource subassemblies
- Support shop-floor assembly, to assure that operators are following the given processes. Continuous optimization of the standard work procedures
- Participates in LEAN initiative, driving AWO actions to completion

## Maintenance Engineer

Samsung - Göd Hungar

October 2003 - May 2007

- Installing new equipment and improve the machines on the production line. Making machine trouble analysis and solving of the systematical machine troubles. Reducing the index time of the production line.
- Programming Sharp and Mithsubishi PLCs, Touch screens, Yaskawa robots, different servo controllers
- Continuously adhered to strict regulations as well as detailed instructions, guidelines and specifications
- Reviewed technical documentation to complete equipment maintenance and repair



Personal portfolio site - A website to present my portfolio

 $\underline{\text{Meetandworkshop}} \text{ - A responsive website created in wordpress for a local co-working office and the state of the$ 

 $\underline{\textbf{Statikusvac}} \text{ - A responsive website created in wordpress for my wife to promote her services}.$ 

<u>TrueNAS SCALE Server</u> - Installed a truenas server in my basement to deploy my personal cloud/data storage, media server and to experiment with other tools/services/containers.



# Károly Lónich

Full Stack Develope (Career Changer)

karoly.lonich@smartcoder.dev

00 36 302573633

smartcoder.dev

in linkedin.com/in/karolylonich

github.com/kal40

#### **EDUCATION**

Full-Stack Web Development Program

CareerFoundry 2022 - present

Explosionproof Technology

Budapest Technical Universit

Integrated Compressor Control Training

General ELectric

Mark VIe Control System Operator and Maintenance Training

General ELectric

BSc in Electrical Engineering Budapest Polytechnic 2000 - 2003

## LANGUAGES

English (Professional)
Hungarian (Native)

## INTERESTS

Running

Hiking

Skiing Leao